<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<CheckList name="Healthy Home Quiz" id="38674ab6-5202-4f5e-9f95-3fe747ed02de">
    <checkListInfo>Use the Healthy Home Quiz to check the health of your home, identify assets and challenges. Use the Tips to minimize indoor pollutants and create a home that promotes wellbeing.</checkListInfo>
    <Category title="Outdoors" id="834d7d56-6535-4c12-8b51-3d031eaa18e0">
        <Question id="9d481fc4-8c87-4597-9101-c4b3a91d675f" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Is your home located next to a busy road or business where cars idle?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Traffic">&lt;p&gt;
      If you live on a busy road or where cars idle you are likely to be 
      subjected to higher levels of motor vehicle pollutants.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Motor vehicles emit exhaust gases into the air such as carbon monoxide, 
      oxides of nitrogen, hydrocarbons and particulates, along with 
      evaporative emission otherwise known as fuel vapours.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      An Australian EPA (Environmental Protection Agency) study (EPA 
      Publication 789) found a link between high levels of fine particles, 
      ozone, nitrogen dioxide and carbon monoxide and an increase in the 
      number of hospital admissions for respiratory and cardiovascular disease.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      If opening your windows subjects you to these fumes you may like to opt 
      for an air purifier to assist you to keep your indoor air clean.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="da87b847-efcd-460d-8926-d468bc5e0163" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you use chemical pesticides around the exterior of the house or garden?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Outdoor pesticides">&lt;p&gt;
      Let's state the obvious - pesticides are designed to kill pests!
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Many pesticides can also pose a risk to human health. In some instances 
      you will not find ingredients listed on the product label as the 
      manufacturer may be protecting their secret formula. But this means you 
      don't really know what chemicals you are using in your home. Just 
      because a product is being sold does not mean it is safe.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      In many countries products such as these are not tested for human health.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Children are more susceptible to pesticides given their size and there 
      is much documented about the connection between pesticides and health 
      issues.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      We like the work of Pesticides.org - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pesticides.org/docs/website-home-use.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.pesticides.org/docs/website-home-use.pdf&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="aae015d9-face-43cc-8cd5-e9993df79fee" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you have any asbestos around the home - exterior cladding, interior cladding, interior tiles, eaves, in heaters, on your shed or garage?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Asbestos">&lt;p&gt;
      If you are unsure whether your home contains asbestos - we strongly 
      suggest you contact a local licensed asbestos assessor to provide a 
      report of asbestos located on your property.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Avoid disturbing asbestos where possible. If removal is necessary, we 
      recommend using a licensed asbestos contractor who will remove and 
      dispose of it safely to avoid harming others.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Asbestos exposure can be fatal years after exposure. Asbestos has been 
      named a carcinogen in many countries.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      For more information relevant to your area contact your local building 
      authority.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Some general information can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asbestos.act.gov.au/about_asbestos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.asbestos.act.gov.au/about_asbestos&lt;/a&gt;.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="57a25955-e411-42fe-ad4f-78fc468ece8c" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Is there evidence of mould around the outside of the house?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Exterior mould">&lt;p&gt;
      Mould around the exterior of the house can impact on the interior 
      materials and quality of air inside the home.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Check that land drainage is adequate, that spouting and down pipes are 
      in good working order and there are no cracks or holes in the roof or 
      wall structures. Excess moisture around the home can lead to mould 
      growth and material deterioration.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Preventing problems early will save you money and prevent mould growth 
      that may impact on your health.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
    </Category>
    <Category title="Interior general" id="f125d392-6456-4eee-a4a5-ef0af4243865">
        <Question id="7c4e7df5-15c9-4190-a042-c1604633f375" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Has your home been freshly painted within the last 2 years?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Freshly painted">&lt;p&gt;
      Freshly painted surfaces are higher in VOCs in the period of time 
      directly after painting. The level of VOCs emitted from paintwork in the 
      home will depend on the type of paint.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Consider opting for low VOC or No VOC brands when choosing paint. You 
      can choose from plant based paints or petroleum based paints. If 
      choosing a petroleum based paint, water based paints are healthier 
      options rather than solvent based paints.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      If starting a painting project it's a good idea to keep children out of 
      freshly painted areas for the first few weeks while the space is aired 
      out and until the highest levels of VOCs have dissipated.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="81ef01d1-3520-47db-ae17-c41ed33cc42e" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you have any plasticised wall paper on your walls?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Wallpaper">&lt;p&gt;
      Plasticised wallpapers may contain PVC that contains volatile organic 
      compounds (VOCs) that off-gas. PVC also contains phthalate chemicals 
      that are found in plastics. Some phthalate chemicals have been found to 
      migrate into household dust and have been linked to asthma.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for paper based wallpaper or fabrics such as linen, silk, sisal, or 
      jute with a water based low VOC adhesive.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="1ecebae2-ef38-4d33-8d1f-f1b2cf084fce" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Are any of your walls made from asbestos sheeting?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Asbestos walls">&lt;p&gt;
      Asbestos is known to cause serious health problems. Asbestos was used to 
      create various products used in housing prior to the mid 1980's and may 
      still be used in some countries. Asbestos sheeting was used for many 
      purposes, often for wet area surfaces hidden behind tiles, for walls, or 
      eaves around a house.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Asbestos contains small particles that if disturbed can cause serious 
      health problems. Have an asbestos audit done on your home and ensure 
      that asbestos is safely removed by a specialist.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Asbestos was also used for many other products and should be avoided or 
      treated with caution.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asbestos&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asbestos&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asbestosadvisor.net/What_does_asbestos_look_like.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.asbestosadvisor.net/What_does_asbestos_look_like.aspx&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="a2084319-12c7-4543-9144-93aa3810cec8" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Is there cracked and peeling paint on any of the walls?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Peeling paintwork">&lt;p&gt;
      Houses painted before 1970 in Australia may have been painted with paint 
      containing high levels of lead. Modern household paints contain less 
      than 1% lead, however renovating or repairing old paint surfaces can 
      expose lead from old paint and can contaminate surfaces and cause lead 
      poisoning.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Small amounts of lead can cause serious health problems particularly for 
      children. Lead has been associated with a wide range of health issues 
      such as behavioural, growth and cognitive issues in children and nervous 
      system, cardiovascular and kidney health issues among others for adults.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Purchase a lead test kit from the local hardware store and test if your 
      old paintwork contains lead before you disturb it. Lead is only a danger 
      once disturbed. Consider repainting the substrate without disturbing the 
      original surface or replace the substrate or hire a professional to 
      remove the lead paint safely.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Refer to the 6 step guide to painting your home - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.environment.gov.au/atmosphere/airquality/publications/leadpaint.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.environment.gov.au/atmosphere/airquality/publications/leadpaint.html&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="3bb1126a-5d13-4210-abc8-17ee19bc1b6f" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you have vinyl floor coverings that are in poor condition?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Vinyl floor coverings">&lt;p&gt;
      A study of phthalates in indoor dust and their association with building 
      characteristics by Gustaf Bornehag and others published by Environment 
      Health Perspectives found a dose response relationship between 
      concentrations of phthalates (plastic softeners) in bedroom dust and the 
      likelihood of being diagnosed with asthma, rhinitis or eczema.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Studies suggest that plastic softeners can find their way into household 
      dust and be inadvertently inhaled.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opting for products free from plastics is a safer alternative for people 
      and the environment.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      For more information on asthma see - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asthma.org.au/Resources.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.asthma.org.au/Resources.aspx&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="d91146b3-18c4-4721-bdb9-bdd81e6bd8af" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Can you see any mould on any of the walls or ceiling in your home?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Mould on walls">&lt;p&gt;
      Mould can cause a range of health issues such as fatigue, weakened 
      immune system and contribute to allergy symptoms.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Mould in the home indicates a problem with moisture and could be a 
      result of a structural problem such as leaks, poor drainage, flooding, 
      rising damp, condensation or humidity. Removing and preventing mould 
      will assist with minimising maintenance expenses but importantly will 
      prevent mould spores from growing and impacting on indoor air quality 
      and your health.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      When moulds are disturbed they release spores into the air, so while 
      cleaning mould ensure you wear a suitable face mask. To clean mould use 
      an 80% naturally fermented white vinegar to 20% water solution.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mould.com.au/mythsaboutmould.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.mould.com.au/mythsaboutmould.htm&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="3f04114d-f538-47f4-a740-46e6b2160d0d" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do your windows open and close properly?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Windows">&lt;p&gt;
      Opening windows can assist with reducing indoor air pollution that has 
      accumulated from building materials and finishes, furniture, household 
      items and lifestyle practices.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      According to a 2012 report by leading global interdisciplinary design 
      firm Perkins+Will, 374 substances that may be found in the home 
      environment were highlighted as known or suspected asthmagens.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="af13f2ed-f13a-47a2-8ba3-481d9c4d7747" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Are window and door screens in good repair?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Screens">&lt;p&gt;
      Opening doors and windows regularly helps with ventilation, pushing 
      stale and often polluted indoor air out.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="fc9123d2-c0fc-456c-9f8f-7c261c73d6bb" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Is there cracked or peeling paint around the windows?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Paintwork dust">&lt;p&gt;
      Old houses may have been painted with paint containing lead. If 
      paintwork is deteriorated chemicals from paintwork are more likely to 
      find their way into household dust that may inadvertently be inhaled or 
      ingested.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Buy a lead test kit from the hardware store before undertaking any DIY 
      repair work as lead paintwork needs to be repaired using protection.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Use a HEPA filter vacuum regularly to minimise the spread of dust 
      throughout the house.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="80b19ff2-e577-4b41-a2f9-06fae1db221f" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>When raining, does water enter windows when they are closed?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Leaking windows">&lt;p&gt;
      Mould needs moisture to start growing - prompt maintenance to repair the 
      water leaks is needed now!
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="20db97f2-baa6-411c-b57e-77c4b2a8e288" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you have plasticised window coverings such as blinds or curtains?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Plasticised window coverings">&lt;p&gt;
      When heated plastics release VOCs (volatile organic compounds), better 
      known as gases or fumes.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Plasticised window coverings receive direct sunlight and heat up in the 
      window and contribute to poor indoor air quality. Some plasticised 
      fabrics can contain phthalate chemicals (plastic softeners) that have 
      been found to migrate into household dust and linked with health 
      concerns.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for window furnishings free from plastics. Natural fibres or 
      naturally treated timber are a great option.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="d28b4f96-db17-4e06-aebd-31306c19eb88" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you use a HEPA vacuum cleaner to remove dust from your house?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="HEPA vacuum">&lt;p&gt;
      HEPA stands for High-Efficiency Particulate Air. A HEPA filter is a type 
      of mechanical air filter that works by forcing air through a fine mesh 
      filter that traps harmful particles.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      A HEPA filter vacuum used to clean the home minimises the spread of 
      household dust that may be polluted with chemicals that have migrated 
      from household products, as well as eliminating pollens, pet dander and 
      dust mites.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="8bfbbc27-cd75-4797-aaca-ae77604ebe39" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you have fluorescent lighting in your home?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Fluorescent lighting">&lt;p&gt;
      Compact fluorescent lighting generally contains mercury. When 
      fluorescent lighting is broken, mercury vapour is released into the air 
      and has been linked to health concerns.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      The long life and low power consumption of these lamps tends to make 
      them a popular choice for homeowners.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for maximising natural lighting within a home through the use of 
      windows strategically placed to gain maximum sunlight or installation of 
      skylights (roof windows). LED lighting is an energy efficient option for 
      those seeking an alternative energy efficient lighting alternative.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      If you break a fluorescent lamp within the home, this should be disposed 
      of with care. You can find more information here - &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www2.epa.gov/cfl/cleaning-broken-cfl/&quot;&gt;http://www2.epa.gov/cfl/cleaning-broken-cfl&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="ba3705af-a2f0-49a8-965f-41c00834a80b" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Have you investigated Radon levels in your home?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Radon">&lt;p&gt;
      Radon is a colorless, odorless, radioactive gas. It forms naturally from 
      the decay of radioactive elements, such as uranium, which can be found 
      at different levels in soil and rock throughout the world.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Radon gas in the soil and rock can move into the air and into homes and 
      has been associated with lung cancer. Different locations around the 
      world have differing levels of Radon.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      You can check radon levels in your home to determine if you need to take 
      action. Do-it-yourself radon detection kits can be ordered through the 
      mail or purchased in some hardware stores. The kits are placed in the 
      home for a period of time and then mailed to a lab for analysis.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Read more about Radon and health concerns - &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.who.int/ionizing_radiation/env/radon/en/&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/ionizing_radiation/env/radon/en/&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      World Health Organisations Handbook on indoor Radon - &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://whqlibdoc.who.int/publications/2009/9789241547673_eng.pdf&quot;&gt;http://whqlibdoc.who.int/publications/2009/9789241547673_eng.pdf&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
    </Category>
    <Category title="Entry" id="d1f70979-b5e1-4502-a019-562951fc3cd2">
        <Question id="d6d1f60d-d52e-40d5-b874-0a107bef74b2" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you have a door mat?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Door mat">&lt;p&gt;
      Door mats assist to trap unwanted particles from entering the home and 
      accumulating in household dust.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      The dust within our homes gets circulated by movement of occupants, 
      heating and cooling systems.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      What is even better than a door mat? Have shoes taken off at the front 
      door!
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="3a4f093a-8b79-4eae-9b3e-a55ad2ca8b3b" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you take your shoes off when entering the house?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Shoes">&lt;p&gt;
      Taking shoes off at the front door prevents germs, bacteria, chemical 
      residues and heavy metals from being walked into the home.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Young children have lots of hand to mouth action and pollutants can be 
      easily ingested from surfaces.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="7d4c5197-b80b-4fc1-87b5-9db29a4e4899" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Upon entering the house do you smell fragrances, eg. air fresheners, incense or candles?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Fragrances">&lt;p&gt;
      Avoid air fresheners, petro chemically produced candles and incense - 
      opt for natural essential oils, plants or flowers.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="18a19b7b-2737-4c93-bcd6-aa62e9ab1dbc" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you smell a musty, damp mould smell?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Musty odour">&lt;p&gt;
      A damp, musty smell indicates that moisture is accumulating somewhere it 
      should not be.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="534f71d7-ed5e-4f37-8000-fd17ea188641" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>While walking around the house can you smell cleaning products? </questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Clean smell">&lt;p&gt;
      Many cleaning products do not list all their ingredients on the label 
      and can contain chemicals that are considered toxic.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Cleaning products leave residues on surfaces around the home creating 
      opportunities for chemicals to be absorbed through the skin, inhaled or 
      ingested.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      A clean odour can have &amp;quot;no&amp;quot; odour.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
    </Category>
    <Category title="Bedrooms" id="93c3ee6a-6bbb-4b0d-91fc-e6b3f246f2d2">
        <Question id="046f87ad-254b-4ef0-b56a-0a9b3f7069dc" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you have plastic in or around your bed, eg. plasticised fabric on the bed frame or plasticised mattress protector?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Beds and plastics">&lt;p&gt;
      
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      In addition to releasing VOCs, plastics can contain phthalates, 
      otherwise known as plastic softeners. Some phthalates have been found to 
      migrate into household dust and been linked to endocrine altering health 
      issues and allergies.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      A Study by Bornehag CG etal titled &amp;quot;The Association between Asthma and 
      Allergic Symptoms in Children and Phthalates in House Dust&amp;quot; showed that 
      &amp;quot;phthalates, within the range of what is normally found in indoor 
      environments, are associated with allergic symptoms in children&amp;quot;.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for natural fibre fabrics such as hemp, cotton, linen and wool. 
      Mattress protectors made from organic cotton or wool are great options.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Read more - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15471731&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/15471731&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="e245103e-77b6-4b1e-b3cb-a6701b78b94e" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you have a mattress that has been treated with a chemical flame retardant?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Flame retardants">&lt;p&gt;
      Some flame retardant chemicals have been found to migrate into household 
      dust and have been linked to a host of health concerns relating to 
      nervous system health, hormonal and thyroid function health among others.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Read more :&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ewg.org/release/new-research-finds-highly-toxic-flame-retardants-widespread-homes-furniture&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.ewg.org/release/new-research-finds-highly-toxic-flame-retardants-widespread-homes-furniture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flame_retardant&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flame_retardant&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="bebe45a8-91e3-479b-85be-d4a2e567f8ca" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you have a mattress that has been treated with a chemical stain guard treatment?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Stain treatments">&lt;p&gt;
      Perfluorinated chemicals (PFCs) are widely-used water, grease and stain 
      repellents. PFCs have been associated with health concerns such as 
      immune suppression, reproductive problems and hormonal disorders.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      PFCs can be found in carpets and furnishings as well as non-stick food 
      packaging.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for products that have not been chemically treated.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="da77a2e7-fb7f-4710-9954-41355c39bdf6" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Are you sleeping on a foam mattress?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Mattress">&lt;p&gt;
      Foams are made from petrochemicals that can offgass into the air that 
      you breathe while sleeping, and many foams contain flame retardant 
      chemicals.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Choose a mattress made from untreated, non-toxic natural materials 
      containing no synthetic chemicals or fire retardants. Opt for a mattress 
      made from natural fibres with NO chemical treatments.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      If a new mattress is not an option buy a wool and organic cotton 
      mattress topper.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="840e8344-c962-4ee2-b61b-ed12e678c431" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you have unsealed particle board or MDF furniture in your bedroom?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Fibre board products">&lt;p&gt;
      The adhesives used to make particle board and MDF (medium density 
      fibreboard) often contain urea formaldehyde.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Formaldehyde can offgass into indoor air. Formaldehyde has been 
      documented to contribute to eye, nose, and throat irritation; wheezing 
      and coughing; fatigue, skin rashes among other more serious health 
      conditions.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for solid timber, metal or glass furniture.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Read more - &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.epa.gov/iaq/formaldehyde.html&quot;&gt;http://www.epa.gov/iaq/formaldehyde.html&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="df8ec237-bcd0-4250-9043-a466cdd504cf" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you have synthetic carpets in your bedroom?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Carpet">&lt;p&gt;
      Toxic chemicals can be found in fibre bonding materials, backing glues, 
      fire retardants, dyes, fungicides and stain resistant treatments.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for carpets made from natural fibres such as wool, sisal, coir or 
      seagrass to minimise VOCs. Avoid chemical treatments such as stain 
      resistance, mothproofing and fungicides. Carpets with woven or jute 
      backing are preferable to rubberised options.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Read more - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.epa.gov/iaq/voc.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.epa.gov/iaq/voc.html&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="f5de96df-ceb6-4f79-bc1c-d1241f2f87df" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you use organic bed sheets?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Organic linen">&lt;p&gt;
      Opt for organic bedding that is produced in accordance with Global 
      Organic Textile Standards where possible. If this is not possible try to 
      buy bed sheets that are Okeo-Tex Certified.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Avoid textiles that have been chemically treated such as stain 
      resistant, crease free and antibacterial chemical treatments.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="e485123e-54e4-4d8a-a273-b5978b23e9e9" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you dry clean your clothes, blankets or other items?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Dry cleaning">&lt;p&gt;
      Tetrachloroethene is a toxic chemical that is widely used in the 
      dry-cleaning of fabrics. Other names for tetrachloroethene include PERC, 
      tetrachloroethylene, perchloroethylene or PCE.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      PERC can contribute to poor indoor air quality and for those with skin 
      sensitivities can contribute to allergy symptoms.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for PERC free cleaning methods such as steam cleaning or hand 
      washing of items. If dry cleaning is necessary, hang the item outdoors 
      until the odour is gone.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Read more - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.atsdr.cdc.gov/tfacts18.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.atsdr.cdc.gov/tfacts18.pdf&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="673c84b3-87fb-4679-9dc9-717d37fa6694" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Is there air flow under your mattress / bed?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Bed airflow">&lt;p&gt;
      Unobstructed space under a mattress encourages air flow circulation and 
      discourages moisture build up in the mattress.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      A bed design with slatted timber supports works well as long as the 
      space under the mattress is free from clutter.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="19c1dcf7-58b9-4226-8c61-d5c09ec46604" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you have sufficient concealed storage in your bedroom?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Storage">&lt;p&gt;
      Minimising dust in the bedroom helps to promote good indoor air quality 
      for optimal health, as dust can circulate with movement, heating and 
      cooling. Dust can contribute to allergies and asthma.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Creating storage that is concealed prevents surface dust from collecting 
      on items over time. Opt for shelving with doors, storage boxes with lids 
      and minimise clutter.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="6e69e98a-dc89-4b2a-8026-66958e505ce7" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you open the window in your bedroom weekly?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Open windows">&lt;p&gt;
      Research has shown that air inside the home is often many times more 
      polluted than the air outside the home.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opening windows regularly will assist to flush out the build-up of VOCs 
      that have accumulated in the indoor air. Even in cooler months a quick 
      burst of outdoor air can help to maintain healthier indoor air for our 
      lungs.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="486ba758-bb29-4d99-b47d-ea52d42651a3" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you sleep next to a clock radio or have any other electrical device turned on nearby, eg. electric blanket?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Electromagnetic fields">&lt;p&gt;
      Could your bedroom design be preventing you from having a restful sleep 
      due to Electromagnetic Fields (EMFs).
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      The issue of EMFs is receiving increasing attention globally in relation 
      to health concerns and health sensitivities. Many hours are spent 
      sleeping. Eliminating sources in the bedroom is a precautionary approach 
      to ensure you get a healthy, good nights sleep.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Remove electrical devices from the bedroom, avoid metal bed frames and 
      mattresses with metal as metal tends to intensify electromagnetic fields.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Are there appliances on walls adjoining the bedroom?
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Keep beds away from appliances on adjoining walls.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Demand switches and other shielding options are available for those who 
      wish to take further action.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      You may like to read more about this contentious issue here - &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.magdahavas.com/international-experts%E2%80%99-perspective-on-the-health-effects-of-electromagnetic-fields-emf-and-electromagnetic-radiation-emr/&quot;&gt;http://www.magdahavas.com/&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
    </Category>
    <Category title="Kitchen" id="21b2cabe-5337-4d2b-9c69-95f334c8915b">
        <Question id="e6ebc3a8-e1ab-4393-bd24-a6230a3c6dc1" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you have a good exhaust fan over the cooking area?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Tissue test">&lt;p&gt;
      The tissue test is a cheap and easy way to test if you have good air 
      extraction from your exhaust fan. Hold a &amp;#189; ply tissue a few centimetres 
      away from the vent. When the fan is on does it draw the tissue up to the 
      vent easily?
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Effective extraction of cooking gasses helps to minimise combustion 
      pollutants that can build up in your indoor air. Combustion pollutants 
      have been linked to health issues.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="40a1ea84-0589-4dba-b4a8-cc17addb0e21" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Are there any signs of mould or mildew in the kitchen, including under the sink?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Removing mould">&lt;p&gt;
      &amp;quot;Occupants of damp or mouldy buildings are at increased risk of 
      experiencing health problems such as respiratory symptoms, respiratory 
      infections, allergic rhinitis and asthma.&amp;quot;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Identify and eliminate the source of moisture. There are various ways to 
      clean mould - we like the 80% naturally fermented white vinegar solution 
      with 20% water.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Read more - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.euro.who.int/__data/assets/pdf_file/0003/78636/Damp_Mould_Brochure.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.euro.who.int/__data/assets/pdf_file/0003/78636/Damp_Mould_Brochure.pdf&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="d138d7b1-9d54-43c8-b665-747f195522b9" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you use non-stick cooking items, eg. pots and pans?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Non stick">&lt;p&gt;
      Perfluorchemicals (PFCs) are commonly used to create non-stick cookware. 
      There is growing concern and information available that PFCs are highly 
      toxic.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for stainless steel, cast iron or glass cookware.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Read more - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.healthybuilding.net/healthcare/2009-04-20PFCs_fact_sheet.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.healthybuilding.net/healthcare/2009-04-20PFCs_fact_sheet.pdf&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="de0a1241-2294-4443-98e3-b4ca7f95ec66" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you use antibacterial hand or dish soap?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Antibacterial">&lt;p&gt;
      Tricolsan is a chemical found in many consumer products including many 
      antibacterial soaps and liquids. According to the Environmental Working 
      group Triclosan has been &amp;quot;linked to liver and inhalation toxicity, and 
      low levels of triclosan may disrupt thyroid function.&amp;quot;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for soaps that use natural ingredients and look for ingredients that 
      you can understand on the label.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="636e2389-6a77-4f22-920c-fe9513901338" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Are the garbage recycling and any compost bins covered?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Rubbish bins">&lt;p&gt;
      Pests like food, moisture and shelter and an open recycling bin is the 
      perfect home.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Keep bins covered to avoid attracting pests. Pests can create a mess, 
      multiple and spread germs.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="7f373616-aa9c-4ce4-83a0-3bf19929fe74" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Are there any signs of pests, eg. droppings or moths, in the kitchen?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Pests">&lt;p&gt;
      Clean up spills quickly and keep surfaces such as bench tops and inside 
      cupboards clean. To minimise the temptation to pests ensure bins are 
      sealed, containers used to store food are kept closed and screens on 
      windows and doors are in good working order.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      If you must use a product to help rid your home of pests opt for 
      chemical free options such as physical traps or non-toxic applications.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="1a46eb56-208f-4127-abd2-a8632cb863b2" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you have a carbon monoxide detector in the kitchen?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Carbon monoxide">&lt;p&gt;
      Carbon monoxide detectors are reasonably inexpensive and may help you 
      detect a gas leak.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Carbon Monoxide known as CO is found in combustion fumes such as those 
      from stoves, gas cooking, gas heating and engine fumes. CO can build up 
      in enclosed spaces without an odour and can cause poisoning.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Common symptoms associated with CO poisoning is headaches, weakness, 
      nausea, vomiting, confusion and chest pain. High levels of Carbon 
      Monoxide can cause loss of consciousness and death.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Detectors help keep your home safe and alert you to any CO leaks.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="2a887ae0-1aa9-4029-8be5-268a51620058" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you use plastic containers to store your food?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Food storage">&lt;p&gt;
      Plastics contain plastic softeners known as phthalates. Phthalates have 
      been known to migrate into food sources while food is being stored. Some 
      phthalates have been linked to hormone disruption health concerns.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for alternatives such as glass, stainless steel or ceramic storage 
      containers.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="2b3b58b8-d8e5-46ca-8029-40166657ce1f" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you use plastic in the microwave?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Microwave ovens">&lt;p&gt;
      Plastics should not be heated, especially near food as chemicals can 
      migrate into the food.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      DEHP is a phthalate (plastic softener) found in some plastics and can 
      particularly migrate into fatty food when heated.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Avoid using plastic in the microwave.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="f5bc7bcb-dab7-4dd8-9cc3-00c3b507fb38" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you drink or eat from pottery items?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Pottery kitchenware">&lt;p&gt;
      Use ceramic cookware from large reputable suppliers.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Look at the label to see if the item guarantees it is lead free. Lead 
      can be used in the glazing process of ceramics and if ingested is 
      harmful. Lead test kits can be purchased from the hardware store.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Don't use old glazed ware for cooking, keep these as decorative items. 
      Wash ceramic cookware by hand and if you notice cracks or chipping 
      replace the item.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="7db54c59-4e70-42b2-add7-889de09263d3" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you check the containers you buy your food in - do they have the plastic ID numbers 3,6 or 7 ?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Plastic IDs">&lt;p&gt;
      Get to know your plastics by checking your food packaging for a small 
      triangle indicating the type of plastic.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Numbers 3, 6 and 7 have been associated with hormone disrupting 
      chemicals. Hormone disrupting chemicals have been linked to early 
      puberty, obesity, development disorders, diabetes and cancer.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Read more at the plastics pocket guide - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ecocycle.org/files/pdfs/pocket_guide_singleprint.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.ecocycle.org/files/pdfs/pocket_guide_singleprint.pdf&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="40391e5a-f086-4bb7-ae2e-2dc915fa0f6f" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you choose organic or pesticide free food options?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Fresh produce">&lt;p&gt;
      Organic food can be expensive. If you are not able to eat organic 
      produce make sure you wash your fresh produce well to remove any 
      pesticide, fungicide or herbicide residue.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      A solution of 10% vinegar with 90% water can be used to soak vegetables 
      and fruit before rinsing to help remove contaminants.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="84c6a52c-2417-487c-9895-c76fd2419b35" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you eat canned goods?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Canned food">&lt;p&gt;
      Many canning companies are placing a lining inside cans that contains 
      Bisphenol A, otherwise known as BPA.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      BPA has been linked to hormonal disruption health concerns. Studies have 
      found that BPA can migrate into the canned food which is then eaten. 
      Given the concern over BPA some companies are using a BPA alternative 
      known as Bisphenol S (BPS), however there is concern mounting that this 
      alternative may also not be safe.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for fresh or frozen food instead.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="6246a649-1399-46c3-8164-7b7431493866" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you use plastic drinking bottles?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Plastic drink bottles">&lt;p&gt;
      To avoid potential plastic softeners from leaching into your beverage 
      opt for stainless steel water bottles free from any internal lining.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="50e24211-30df-4cc1-a5c7-e940db3bc61f" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you filter your drinking water?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Water">&lt;p&gt;
      Water supplies around the world vary greatly as does the type of 
      treatment given to public water supplies. Using a water filter can 
      remove bacteria, pesticides, lead, copper, iron, chlorine, nitrates and 
      fluoride (depending on the filter used).
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Clean water is essential for good health. In instances where family 
      members have skin conditions removing harsh irritants such as chlorine 
      can also be beneficial.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
    </Category>
    <Category title="Bathroom" id="093ee4e8-5ab1-44ae-83e2-5b27b6fb2b5c">
        <Question id="cba7de3b-aade-426a-90f9-c541ba0d529e" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Is there a musty mould smell in the bathroom?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Bathroom mould">&lt;p&gt;
      Safely remove the mould and fix the cause.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Tips to avoiding mould in the bathroom are:
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        Shorter, cooler showers minimises the build-up of steam
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        Use a ceiling exhaust fan during and shortly after showering to remove 
        steam and help dehumidify the air
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        If the bathroom has a window keep it open when possible for air 
        circulation
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        Wipe down wet surfaces after finishing in the bathroom
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        Clean the bathroom regularly to avoid mould growth
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        Hang towels where they will dry as wet towels in a bathroom all day 
        create a damp environment.
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="180bac5a-3562-48a7-bf53-39e4ed4a9b8f" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you see any signs of water damage?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Water damage">&lt;p&gt;
      Mould thrives in damp areas. A common area for mould growth in the 
      bathroom is under silicone sealant around tiles. Remove the sealant, 
      clean the area well, ensure it is dry and then reseal with a wet area 
      low VOC sealant.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Tea tree oil is effective in cleaning mould. A 3% solution or 2 
      teaspoons in a spray bottle with 2 cups of water (shake well) can be 
      used as an alternative to a vinegar solution.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="c5b7637a-23ca-4da3-a5d3-6c23493bef55" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Does water condense on the inside of the window?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Water condensation">&lt;p&gt;
      Condensation is a common cause of dampness in buildings, often occurring 
      on cold walls, windows and floors, but it can also occur in roof spaces 
      and in sub-floor areas.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      To minimise condensation increase ventilation by using fans for air 
      circulation or opening a window.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      In cooler months indoor temperature throughout the home should ideally 
      be kept at a constant even temperature to warm surfaces.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Insulate cold surfaces.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Remove moisture sources such as drying wet clothes indoors.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Install a dehumidifier if required.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="09438290-c7fe-4217-9254-75680f6ca7bf" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Is there a working exhaust fan over the shower?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Bathroom exhaust">&lt;p&gt;
      The tissue test is a cheap and easy way to test if you have good air 
      extraction from your exhaust fan.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Hold a &amp;#189; ply tissue a few centimetres away from the vent. When the fan 
      is on does it draw the tissue up to the vent easily?
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Install a closure device to the top of your exhaust fan that only opens 
      when in use to prevent heat loss and pest access.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="bbf86cd1-43da-49f7-ae39-1501f330d708" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you have a plastic or PVC shower curtain?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Plastic shower curtain">&lt;p&gt;
      A Study by the Center for Health, Environment &amp;amp; Justice (USA) found PVC 
      shower curtains can release as many as 108 volatile organic compounds 
      (VOCs) into the air.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for PVC-free shower curtains made out of safer materials such as 
      organic cotton, nylon, polyester.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Read more at - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chej.org/showercurtainreport/documents/Volatile%20Vinyl%20Executive%20Summary.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.chej.org/showercurtainreport/documents/Volatile%20Vinyl%20Executive%20Summary.pdf&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="e71e97b7-5f63-4094-9b40-a6242ca3a292" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you use antibacterial hand soap?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Soap">&lt;p&gt;
      Triclosan is an anti-bacterial chemical used in many anti-bacterial 
      soaps and products.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Tricolan has been linked to liver, thyroid and endocrine (hormone 
      development) disorders in children.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      The over use of antibacterial products may lead to germs becoming immune 
      to them and develop into superbugs that are not easily treated with 
      antibiotics.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      See how the World Health Organisation says you get clean hands - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.who.int/gpsc/clean_hands_protection/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.who.int/gpsc/clean_hands_protection/en/&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="5745b0e3-598d-4e00-9031-576eda0f5bb2" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you use non-toxic, natural ingredient hair products?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Hair products">&lt;p&gt;
      What we use to wash our hair with impacts on our skin and can be 
      irritating.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Avoid Sodium Lauryl Sulphate which is a widely used synthetic detergent 
      found in many personal items.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Check out David Suzuki's dirty dozen guide - &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://davidsuzuki.org/dirty12/#wrapper&quot;&gt;http://davidsuzuki.org/dirty12/#wrapper&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="df4d111b-84d5-42cb-83e4-1688e7515e86" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you use non-toxic, natural ingredient personal care products?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Personal care products">&lt;p&gt;
      Have you read the label - do you really know what you are using?
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Your skin is your bodies largest organ and is capable of absorbing 
      products used.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Did you know that formaldehyde is used in many personal care products?
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Did you know that formaldehyde is classified a probable carcinogen?
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for products made from natural organic ingredients where possible.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Look for products that are independently certified.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Look for companies that are transparent with their ingredients.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      For more tips about personal care products visit the Environmental 
      Working Group Skin Deep database - &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.ewg.org/skindeep/&quot;&gt;http://www.ewg.org/skindeep&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      We love the transparent, organic, independently certified natural 
      products by Miessence, check them out here - &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.miessence.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.miessence.com&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
    </Category>
    <Category title="Laundry" id="236c10a5-8113-4149-a79a-bf8046180df2">
        <Question id="c0b86baa-ab3f-43a3-89bc-56e45114a668" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you use non-toxic, washing products?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Washing">&lt;p&gt;
      Many ingredients used to create washing powders are not mentioned on the 
      product label and are untested for human health.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Harsh washing powders can irritate the skin. Fabric softeners and 
      scented drying products made from toxic chemicals subtly coat washing. 
      Synthetic fragrances are among the world's top allergens and are 
      suspected of being endocrine disruptors.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for products with NO synthetic surfactants, no artificial fragrance, 
      no bulking agents or fillers.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="9e9f67e1-d156-472f-9f5e-531a4861c3cb" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Does water condense on the walls and ceilings when using appliances in the laundry?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Laundry moisture">&lt;p&gt;
      Efficient ventilation and an exhaust fan is needed in the laundry to 
      prevent moisture damaging the laundry room or making its way into other 
      rooms of the house and encouraging mould growth.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="df81b6d5-e129-4b94-9065-e658faa15f6b" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Is your clothes dryer vented to the outside of the house? </questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Drying appliance">&lt;p&gt;
      Venting the air externally will prevent excess moisture indoors. If the 
      unit is not vented it may cause condensation and encourage mould growth. 
      Venting into the roof cavity can also cause moisture issues to 
      insulation and building materials.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for external release of moisture sources where possible.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="efe3fc79-e175-413b-8500-d298e2ba744a" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you store paints and garage related products in your laundry?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Garage items inside">&lt;p&gt;
      Products can offgass while being stored.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Keep paints, coatings and chemicals safely stored outside the house to 
      avoid off gassing and polluting indoor air.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
    </Category>
    <Category title="Lifestyle practices" id="c25ce223-e471-4774-bbbe-81c9fe2c9550">
        <Question id="31817478-6d8a-474c-bc2b-f0499def6a5c" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you dry clean your clothes?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Dry cleaning clothes">&lt;p&gt;
      Tetrachloroethylene is often used in the dry-cleaning process and this 
      chemical is classed a category 3 carcinogen and has been documented as 
      having the potential to cause skin irritation.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      If dry cleaning is necessary, hang dry cleaned clothes outside for a 
      while after collecting to minimise the fumes before putting them away 
      indoors.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="906ade10-135c-474a-bd8e-99c4e6b0501c" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you use microfiber cloths for dusting?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Dusting">&lt;p&gt;
      Microfibre clothes attract dust to the cloth surface and reduce dust 
      from being airborne.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Many household chemicals migrate into dust such as flame retardants, 
      stain resistant and insecticide chemicals.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="19370208-f17d-4e63-86c5-c0f7d7efbcc0" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you use a HEPA vacuum filter?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="HEPA filter">&lt;p&gt;
      HEPA stands for High Efficiency Particulate Air filter.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Air and dust is forced through a fine mesh filter trapping small 
      particles of dust, pollens, pet dander and other pollutants to prevent 
      them from being circulated when cleaning and therefore assists with the 
      quality of your indoor air.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="9374a151-46ab-4fd0-b808-611d73f5d86a" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you use environmentally friendly cleaning products?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Eco cleaning">&lt;p&gt;
      Look for manufacturers who list ALL their ingredients on the label.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Contact the consumer number on the label and ask for a copy of the 
      Material Safety Data Sheet so you understand what you are using and the 
      hazards.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="cd5b9f24-7dd8-4154-a131-1621d9dd3a1d" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you ask guests to take their shoes off at the door?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Visitor's shoes">&lt;p&gt;
      Put a large door mat outside doors.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      People walk all sorts of pollutants such as pesticides, heavy metals and 
      germs indoors via dust on their shoes.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="c443ac23-62c9-4e05-881d-79792148c1d9" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you use fragrance products inside the home, eg. stand-alone scents, plug ins?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Natural fragrances">&lt;p&gt;
      Synthetic fragrances are one of the world's top allergens and are also 
      suspected of being endocrine disruptors.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for natural fragrances such as flowers.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="cecf4da3-931f-4a15-84e8-3f802202fdd7" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you leave your car idling in the driveway?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Car">&lt;p&gt;
      Exhaust fumes can potentially contain carbon monoxide, nitrogen dioxide, 
      benzenes, sulphur dioxide, lead, formaldehyde and particulate matter.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Vehicle emissions are toxic and can make their way indoors if stationery 
      for extended periods of time.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="4fad6e0a-7e43-4413-a546-02474a48fb72" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you use an open fire in your home?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Wood fire">&lt;p&gt;
      Wood smoke is a mixture of gasses and particles that are airborne. Wood 
      smoke has been documented by many organisations as impacting on human 
      health particularly on susceptible people such as those with heart and 
      lung disease, asthma and small children.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="05db5ad9-edff-41e6-baa2-4036e2574ba1" yesIsBad="false">
            <questionText>Do you have indoor plants?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Indoor plants">&lt;p&gt;
      A study by NASA has shown that indoor house plants have been shown to 
      remove various toxins from indoor air such as formaldehyde, benzene, 
      xylene among others.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      To learn more about the type of plants studied read &amp;quot;How to Grow Fresh 
      Air&amp;quot; available here - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.healthyinteriors.com.au/shop/products/great-books/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;http://www.healthyinteriors.com.au/shop/products/great-books/&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="bb2ebc01-747f-48f2-9707-9cc835e03e4d" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Does anyone smoke indoors?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Smoking">&lt;p&gt;
      Tobacco smoke will pollute indoor air and has been shown to cause cancer.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      A healthy family is a great reason to give up or ask visitors to smoke 
      outdoors away from windows and doors to prevent smoke entering the house.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
        <Question id="7ea6fc94-1247-4746-9cb4-5c1eae9ff658" yesIsBad="true">
            <questionText>Do you spray pesticides in the house or use pest free plug ins?</questionText>
            <questionInfo title="Pesticides">&lt;p&gt;
      Airborne pesticide products pollute indoor air and can potentially be 
      inhaled.
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
      Opt for natural pest remedies where possible or physical type baits or 
      traps that do not spread chemicals throughout the home.
    &lt;/p&gt;</questionInfo>
        </Question>
    </Category>
</CheckList>
